Last week, Antropic and OpenAI, yeah,
that's a big company, shipped their own
Frontier models, Opus 4.7 and Codex 5.5.
The whole timeline is telling you that
the best model is the one they're going
to use. We're going to do that, too. But
we're going to compare that and we're
going to even go deeper. If you want to
know how to use those models, stay watch
this video, subscribe to the channel,
and yeah, that's it. Enjoy. Bye. So, how
was your first impression of first?
Yeah. 4.7 and 5.5. Michelle,
>> 4.7 was like all token spend in 10
minutes and the first on 5.5 was all
token spent in 20 minutes, but they made
an update.
>> Yes. And since then it works.
>> Yeah. And even on 4.6 it's still better.
>> Yeah, that's that's what I think. So
like I prefer 4.6.
>> You are using it for orchestration of
the entire product and you're having 5.5
doing the coding. players. I still plan
with Opus and I I I do I run the Codex
Adversary review and execute with 5.5.
>> I'm just keep swapping because it feels
like every week they have a different
way of working and a different output.
>> Yeah.
>> I I don't even know which one to trust
properly to just set it as a default to
continue coding all the time.
>> Yeah. No, 100%. one week to another like
the whole harness on their side on the
like entropic servers and OpenAI server
stuff changed and it [__] up
everything. It's kind of like annoying.
>> Also, the amount of tokens you can burn.
I was using Cordex 5.5 on my business
account, but the business account is is
smaller. You have less amount of tokens.
So I swapped to the pro account and
before I was out in like 20 minutes my
five 5 hour limit was reached and now
I'm at 98% after four hours of work.
>> When you have entropic like throttling
everyone and and introducing like peak
hours limit and then you have open AAI
guys just resating the limit because
it's it's what it's Tuesday. I mean the
choice is a no-brainer. GPT 5.5 plus OPU
4.7 or 4.6 you have a good stack.
>> Yeah. Yeah. It should be the just the
basic and you can just let them check
each other. So it should be no problem.
>> Basically we use our shitty promp for
4.6 to 4.7 and then the quy is [__]
because it almost doesn't work the same
way.
>> Yeah. And then it thinks I will do it
for you. It starts burning tokens going
searches and you will get something
completely different than you asked.
>> 20% more expensive.
>> Yeah. But if you can use it to do it
properly by having chip by codeex 5.5
writing the prompt in details then it
should be fine. If you need to do a
different prompting just to use the
>> exactly
>> model in the optimal way then do the
benchmarks even make sense because you
the benchmark is the same prompt for
every model.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I mean, yeah, you
still want to push some output on new
ways to code for like not GPT but like
Opus 5 for example. You can prepare
people to even if you lose the benchmark
first but you prepare for the next
generation.
>> Do you ever ask the question what could
I have prompted differently and how
could I have differently asked the
question to get a better result?
>> Not really. I just like fix that [__]
>> Yeah. Okay.
>> Do you?
>> Yeah. Yeah, I do. I ask it what could I
because sometimes you just get the first
output and it's really bad.
>> Yeah.
>> And then you're like working for 30
minutes to get the result that you want
and that's the moment when I ask okay
what could I have asked you in the
initial prompt to get this result
directly and please give me a few steps
and I write those down and when creating
the next prompt I just put those steps
in.
>> Okay. So and do you create a skill to
ask but like a prompt engineer skill
stuff? Yeah. I just don't I don't
install the skills. I just
>> put them, but you can write them for you
for yourself, right?
>> Yeah. Yeah. And I choose which ones to
just include. The thing is 5.5 is really
smart.
>> Yeah.
>> I get faster to the results that I want
and I have to correct it less times.
>> Yeah.
>> So even if it's double in tokens, I
don't mind because it understands
exactly what I want in like one or two
questions instead of six.
>> Yeah. Yeah. But like see like 5.5 is way
more efficient than 5.4. So yeah,
>> yeah, like there's no point of staying
on 5.5. So even for us, you can plan
with entropic and use 5.5 low to execute
the plan that you have with from
entropic.
>> Yeah, but yeah, from codec. But I would
still say you can also just use X high
for planning and use the low for coding
and then use X high again for checking.
>> Is that what you do inside the CLI?
Because now you can plan you can set the
effort on planning and executing right
>> well before with now in Codex I didn't
set it up but before with Opus when I
was using 4.6
>> I would use the most smartest model the
highest model on planning and I say you
are not allowed to code you need to
spawn agents that code and I would use
sonet to do all the coding. Okay. Yeah.
Oh yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. So, okay. So,
you plan and like the when you exit the
plane, the sub agent are triggered and
they use sun.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And they report back to the
main agent that's using the opus the the
high model.
>> Yeah.
>> And he checks the code that he gets. But
I'm still using codeex as well, but he
is just checking the plan that was made
by Opus.
>> Yeah. Then Yeah. Okay. So then ship code
is useful when you use both and not just
one.
>> Yeah. Exactly.
>> Love it. because I see that even if I
say to opus I want to have three
different approaches to tackle this
problem and all three are still similar
it's just like it's stuck in a in a
certain way of thinking but then I use
op I use codeex and I say I need two
additional ways to tackle this problem
and I get totally different approaches
and I merge them both into one by saying
to opus hey check the other two that
were created by Codex and then he says
oh that's a great idea I can merge merge
it into my ideas, cross reference
problem approaches by different models
and that works really good. And two
weeks ago if I I had them merge all the
ideas into one plan of how to approach
and how to build it and I made a final
question to both of them to Opus and to
Codex and my final question was which of
the models need to do the coding and
which of the models needs to do the
checking and both of them agreed. Damn.
Both of them said Opus needs to do the
coding and Kodak needs to do the checks
and and the feedback.
>> That's crazy.
>> And I would imagine that Codex would say
no, I'm better at coding and Opus the
same way. But both of them said you need
to let Opus do the coding.
>> Did you workflow like recently or it was
like something you did six month?
>> No, I've been doing this like like for
two or three months already every week
on different projects
>> and you get different result.
>> Yes. So that's why I think it's
impossible to fully automate the entire
flow because you will miss after an
update. You will miss opportunities.
>> Well, that means like you you have to
force it. You have to force the flow
like you don't ask the agent, oh yeah,
which one should go. It's like you you
set up you you opinionated the workflow
and you lock it like you put the guard
rail. So you lose that that maybe the
evaluation of the model or you have one
more model that's evaluating always only
doing that. So if you don't have the
syncing in instead of using your
component you have defined like six
months ago is going to use the HTML tag
blue.
>> Yeah. Yeah. But is there a way to just
automatically switch the model like low,
medium, high depending on the question
that I ask?
>> Is it is it doing efficiently?
>> I don't know. Is it possible to have it
analyze my question, make an an estimate
on what model it needs to do and then
switch the model and perform?
>> I don't know. I think it changed the f
like I'm not sure but I think entropic
has auto mode on effort. No.
>> Yeah. But I don't trust the auto mode. I
think
>> so then then that's what you were
thinking like you need to build your own
auto like the effort routter.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Instead of trusting the entropic
that's going to charge you at the end of
the month anyway, right? So yeah like a
spawn sub agent to isolate context
paralyze independent work offload bulks
mechanical task that's basically what
you're doing. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
For sure.
>> Pick the cheapest model that can do the
subtask well. AU B mechanical no
judgment. Sun scope research code
exploration and opus subtask needed real
planning. So you're good. You're good
usage. Good job.
>> Yeah. And some you have to test.
>> Yeah. And yeah the clo disable one
minute context. This one this features
is useless bro. Disable it. Same thing
for auto compact at 80%. I do that too
and I have better result too I think. So
lock to model session start having MCP.
I I don't have any MCP running except
context 7. I I yeah I mean two years ago
MCP were like burning context. I don't
know if they are better now. I don't
have any.
>> I don't know. The only thing I know is
that my customers that do use an MCP
they are out of token so fast but they
just they also because it's so easy to
ask information they use it for
everything.
>> Context bloke keeps rereading the files.
Let's go. system prompt clear compact.
Yeah. A compact sub agent and rewind.
Did you ever use rewind?
>> Nope.
>> Disable 1 million 1 million context and
80% 200k context is plenty to do that.
Just take to spawn them. They run in a
clean window. So that's what you do,
right? With with your plan.
>> Yes.
>> Load lean. Move rules to skills to
custom custom
custom tools. The [__] reference MD5
progressive disclosure disable unus MTP
yeah whatever keep the search reference
search task close to great okay I don't
use it compact at 50% or after every
task okay after about no try keep a
failure in context for new text no try
keeps the failure in context okay
interesting okay maybe maybe we should
start rewind quality op 4.7 is excite
if there race to max for dement work.
Yeah. Yeah. But like if you do that
>> Yeah, I did it in my settings because it
was burning so many tokens.
>> Yeah, exactly. Spell out when to use OP
Sony AU. Okay, we saw that too. GBT 5
5.5 is 34% cheaper than 4.7 like what I
thought it was.
>> I think this is this shows that it
depends on how do you use it, what
prompts do you give it, etc., etc., etc.
And that all gives you a different
result each time.
>> It's It's nuts.
>> And then people put it in a chart and
they just post it and everybody's happy.
>> Yeah. 100K views. Let's go.
>> Yeah. We still need conclusion, right?
Which model is better?
>> Yeah. You want to conclude?
>> I want to conclude. It doesn't matter
which model you use. You just have to
give the proper input.
>> Yeah.
>> And use both.
>> Use both. Have them correct each other.
>> So, let's go. Uh thank you so much. Uh
we will see you all uh next week.
Subscribe to the channel. Uh like, share
with your dev friends and non-dev
friends because we need people on the
channel. So ch
>> and uh yeah, see you next week. Bye
>> bye.
>> Bye. Why?